When I was little, I wanted
to be a champion of justice.
What?
You wanted to be one?
Did you give up?
Yeah.
It's unfortunate, but...
Being a hero is a
limited-time thing.
When you grow up, it gets
hard to call yourself one.
I should have
realized that earlier.
I see.
That's just too bad, then.
Indeed.
You're absolutely right.
Yeah.
Since you couldn't
do it, I'll do it for you.
You're an adult now,
so you can't do it.
But I can.
Just leave your dream to me.
Right.
Yeah.
I can be at peace now.
In the face of absolute despair
That nearly burned
our hearts away
You still found the
courage to smile
Like you accepted it all
I lost my voice
And the things I wanted to say
But every time I
fell to my knees
I stood up and kept walking
We were looking for
the ideal white future
Our one and only hope
Now I may be left with nothing
But these raging
emotions that have
Nowhere to go
Still, I'll look for a new dawn
With more than one right answer
I won't stop
Until I find it
So what was this urgent
errand from Kuzuki-sensei?
Dancing After School
I don't know.
All she said was,
"I have to finish an errand from
Kuzuki-sensei tonight, or else.
Oh, and try to get along,
Sakura-chan and Saber-chan."
She didn't go into detail.
She just left after that.
Jeez, she's the one who suggested
you stay over, and then she bails.
But it's okay. It gave me a chance
to chat with Saber-san about things.
Yes. Sakura and I
have broken the ice.
Come on, I'll be fine.
There'll be lots of
people at school.
Besides, didn't the school pass
your safety inspection yesterday?
Shirou, that was yesterday.
That doesn't mean
that it's still safe today.
If you're gonna be like that, I
won't ever be able to go anywhere.
And besides, you need to conserve
your mana, so get some rest.
Very well, if that is
your decision, Master.
However, do not hesitate to use a Command
Spell if you think you're in danger.
Got it. See you later.
Hey.
What? Do I have
something on my face?
Self-Study
STUDENT COUNCIL ROOM
Issei, aren't you
going to eat lunch?
I'll eat later.
I just want to sleep right now.
Oh? Did you stay up all night?
No, I just haven't been
sleeping well lately.
Issei, someone's here.
I don't care! Tell them the
student council is closed!
It's Kuzuki-sensei.
Ryuudou, I need to speak to you.
Yes, sir.
Then she hasn't
returned home, either?
I know.
Pardon the intrusion.
After-school activities are likely
to be canceled, so take note.
Yes, sir.
What was that about?
Well...
Hey, Issei?
Well, you're not exactly an outsider,
so I guess it's okay for you to hear this.
Late last night,
the faculty office got a
call from a family saying
their daughter hadn't come
home from archery practice.
After calling the
other team members,
the teachers determined that Shinji was the
last one to talk to the missing student.
Shinji?
But Shinji wasn't at
practice yesterday.
Apparently, a first-year student
forgot something at the dojo,
and when he came back for it, he saw
Shinji and the missing student arguing.
We tried to confirm
this with Shinji.
But he's absent today, and no
one's been able to reach him.
Don't keep me in
suspense, Issei.
Who's the missing student?
Mitsuzuri Ayako,
the captain of the archery team.
Did you notice anything odd
about Shinji's behavior yesterday?
I'm sorry, Senpai.
I haven't seen him
very often lately either.
That's right. You
wouldn't know anything.
Sorry, I shouldn't
have asked you that.
No, that's not true.
I know my brother
better than anyone.
Well, it's not something
you should be worrying about.
See you.
All after-school club
activities are canceled today.
The library will also be closed.
Students with no urgent business are
asked to leave school grounds at once.
I repeat...
If you're looking for Ayako-chan,
she's home sick today.
Oh, thanks.
If Mitsuzuri comes tomorrow,
don't mention this, okay?
Okay...
Huh? Tohsaka?
Unbelievable.
Are you crazy, coming to
school without your Servant?
What choice did I have?
Saber can't dematerialize,
so I can't bring her.
Then stay home from school.
A Master strolling
around without his Servant
might as well have "Please
kill me" painted on his back.
Emiya-kun, do you have any
idea just how big of an idiot you are?
Idiot?
Masters don't fight with
other people around, right?
So it should be
perfectly safe at school.
Then tell me this:
do you see anyone else here?
Huh?
Wait...
Finally sinking in, I see.
Seriously, this morning, I went
from exasperated to furious.
"After all I told him, why is he doing
everything he can to get himself killed?"
A magic crest...
Yes, this is the manifestation of
the magic passed down in my family.
I can invoke any spell etched here
by simply passing mana through it.
I've sent Archer away.
The Gandr Shot here
will suffice for you.
Gandr? Isn't that just
a simple Nordic curse?
That's right. A
perfectly simple curse.
W-Wait, Tohsaka!
Are you crazy? We're at school!
If we make a scene, who
knows who might turn up?
I'll worry about that
when it happens.
My policy is not to miss an
opportunity when it presents itself.
Sorry, Emiya-kun, but I'll
take you out here and now.
Besides, I don't think my nerves could
take much more of your bumbling around.
Wait, damn it!
I don't want to fight you...
Well, I want to fight you!
Just prepare yourself, Shirou!
That was Gandr?
It's nothing like the one I
know! Are you trying to kill me?
I thought I made that clear!
Hold it right there!
Ow!
You could seriously hurt
someone with those things!
If you're scared of a
little pain, just stand still!
I'll finish you off quickly!
If they hit a vital spot,
you'll die instantly!
That doesn't sound
like a mercy killing!
Shut up! Then
quit running around!
I'm getting worked up because
my target won't stand still!
Oh, crap!
- Das Schließen Vogelkäfig... Echo!
- The locking, bird cage... Echo!
She put up a magic field!
Fixierung, Eilsalve!
Fixation, speed volley!
Trace on!
She's out of mana?
So you finally came
out, Emiya-kun?
Put down that silly weapon.
You don't have a chance
of winning, Emiya-kun.
I won't know until I try.
Oh, really?
Well, this is your
final warning.
Put down your weapon, and
hold out your Command Spells.
At worst, I'll strip
the nerves from your
arm, but better to lose
those than your life.
No. I will not give you
the Command Spells.
That's no different from
telling me to betray Saber.
I see.
I'll give you three seconds.
It's your life, so
it's your decision.
Time's up. Emiya-kun,
what's your decision?
Tohsaka, was that...
A scream?
Wait, Emiya-kun!
It looks like she's
just unconscious.
She isn't just unconscious! Can't
you see she's been drained dry?
Drained dry?
Of her mana. Her
life force, if you like.
She hardly has any blood left.
If we don't do
something, she'll die.
Die? Hey, Tohsaka...
I should be able to
stabilize her with this gem.
Tohsaka...
Look out!
Wh-What is that?
Why did you...
Never mind that, you're
bleeding! You're bleeding badly!
D-Doesn't it hurt?
It does. Like you
wouldn't believe.
Tohsaka, take care of her.
Wha...
A Servant!
She vanished?
I'm surprised. You aren't
going to use a Command Spell?
Sorry. I don't have many left.
I see.
Unlike my Master,
you possess courage.
In that case, I will take
a different approach.
I shall grant you
a merciful death.
Compared to the other Servants,
you aren't very impressive.
You don't pack any punch.
No, this is the end for you.
I've had you in the palm
of my hand all along.
Now, then. What was that interesting
thing you were saying before?
Something about my being
inferior to other Servants?
I'm afraid we can't have that.
I'll start by plucking out those
eyes that were so dearly mistaken.
Then I'll move on to your limbs.
Emiya-kun, are you all right?
W-We have to stop the bleeding!
Emiya-kun, do you have
anything I can wrap it with?
Uh... Oh, I have a handkerchief.
Sakura always
prepares one for me.
Like minds, huh?
But it's better than nothing.
Together with my
towel, we can make do.
So, that woman was a Servant?
Yeah. She attacked
out of nowhere.
Don't look at me like that.
I couldn't tell who it
was, but doesn't that
mean there's another
Master here besides us?
They've finally made
their move, huh?
Okay, I've patched
you up for now.
Tohsaka, what
happened with that girl?
She's recovering. I
think she'll pull through.
Ah.
That's good.
Why are you staring
at me like that?
J-Just so you know, I'd
never do something like that!
Listen, I know.
You'd never do that.
I'm talking about our fight.
Want to continue?
Tohsaka? I mean...
What do you want to do?
No, thanks. Let's call it a day.
For one thing, I owe you again.
Okay, let's go.
We need to get
your wound treated.
Please bear with it
until we get to my place.
Your place?
Put simply, there's
another Master at school
who's preyed on many
students like that girl.
Why would they do that?
To win the Holy
Grail War, of course.
Their plan is to sacrifice the students
to strengthen their own Servant.
Are they nuts?
Who knows? But there's already a
magical field set up around the school.
Once it's activated, it will probably
drain the life force from everyone inside.
Emiya-kun...
Coming from me,
you might reject this,
but I think we
should call a truce.
A truce? Between you and me?
I want to deal with
this other Master first.
So until then, want to call a truce
and help me track them down?
Well? Personally, I
think it's a good deal.
Sure, having your help will
make me feel a lot better.
I'm not really helping you. We've
simply agreed to a ceasefire.
But as long as you don't betray
me, I'll assist you, Emiya-kun.
So we'll be partners for life,
then. Let's do our best, Tohsaka.
It won't be quite that long,
but try to make yourself useful.
Now I understand.
You aren't a legitimate heir.
Your father died before he could
pass his magic crest on to you.
I'm not so sure.
He was always against
my becoming a mage.
Isn't that contradictory?
Maybe.
It always seemed like Dad only
taught me because I refused to give up.
In the end, he only
taught me fortifying magic,
so that's all I can use.
Hold on! Why would
you tell me that?
Tohsaka?
Look, Emiya-kun, we might
be partners for the time being,
but mages should always
keep their arts a secret.
What's the point
of hiding it now?
Dad always said that magic isn't something
you should go out of your way to hide.
He really said that?
Yeah. I think he was trying to tell
me not to let myself be bound by rules.
He always said I should
quit if I ever want to.
That's ridiculous! Your
father was no mage!
And if he trained you, you're
no mage either in my eyes!
Why are you so upset?
I know I can't call myself a mage,
but my dad was the real deal.
That's not what I mean.
I'm trying to say...
Well...
Yeah, I do have a problem
with your incompetence.
What can I do?
My old man's dead.
Yeah, that's the inherent
limit of a single mage.
Mages never know when they'll die,
so they leave behind a magic crest.
I was just angry at your father for
not taking the proper steps to prepare.
Magic is the culmination
of lifetimes of work,
handed down from parent to
child for generation after generation.
The instant a child is
born into a mage family,
that child inherits not only
their legacy but also their duty.
That's the reason we're
born, and it's what we die for.
A mage family's duty is to take
the human child they gave birth to
and turn it into something else
over long years of rigorous training.
That's why your father
was no mage, Emiya-kun.
He put being a father
ahead of being a mage.
We didn't understand anything
My left hand groped for
things that vanished to my touch
A moral conflict
stays your hand
and tricks you
out of your future
I don't know how
to protect anyone,
and my ideals might
well be pointless,
but I want to live my life
The past repeats before my eyes
Here I will trust the me
that now stands with you
Until my dream
crumbles and withers,
I hope you will carve
out paradise with me
Fight your fate
Is this Ryuudou Temple?
Please don't be so stiff, Emiya.
All the people in this
town belong to me.
I may be inexperienced,
but I am still a mage.
If you wish to pass, then
force your way through.
Mirage
Next Time